starone.org 2010-06-16

# Star One Credit Union - Privacy

## Star One Credit Union Privacy Policy

### Our Privacy Pledge

At Star One Credit Union, we respect the privacy of our members. We recognize the importance of maintaining the confidentiality of your personal financial information. This notice describes the privacy policy and practices followed by Star One Credit Union. This notice explains what types of member information we collect and under what circumstances we may share it.

**We do not sell member information nor share your account numbers with independent third party marketers offering their products and services.**

#### Member Information We Collect

The Credit Union collects relevant information about members that is needed to establish and maintain your account and services as the law allows or requires us to collect. We may collect personal and financial information about you (member information) which is "nonpublic." The member information we collect varies depending on the accounts and services you request and use. We collect information about you from the following sources:

_Application Information._ We retain personal information we receive from you on any application you provide for membership, deposit accounts, EFT services, loans, insurance, or other Credit Union services. This information includes: name, address, social security number, birth date, phone number, employment and financial status, and credit history.

_Your Transactions._ Any time you make a transaction on one of your accounts, including ATM or card transactions, loan advances, or insurance transactions, transactions through Online Banking, or over the phone or at a branch, we retain the transaction information, including: your account number, the date, amount, location of the transaction, and other pertinent information.

_Credit Reports._ When we evaluate your application for an account or service, we may request a credit report about you from a consumer reporting agency. We retain the personal and credit history information about you and we may use it to evaluate future account service requests.

_Online._ We obtain information online when you visit our web site, https://www.starone.org. This includes retaining information you provide us on any online application, Online Banking transaction or information you send to us by e-mail.

#### Member Information We Share

In order to provide financial services to you, we share certain information about you with our third party service providers to the extent necessary to service your account or services. If we share your information, it is with the goal of bringing you quality services, more choices, and greater convenience. Information we may have about former members is generally shared or disclosed if necessary to enforce or administer an account or as required by law.

_Sharing Information with Third Party Service Providers._ In order for us to conduct our operations, including servicing your account or processing your transactions, we need to share information with our service providers, including: data processing companies, check, ATM, and other payment processing companies, payment networks, loan service providers, insurance companies, collection agencies, and credit reporting agencies. These service providers act on our behalf and have agreed in writing to keep the member information we provide to them confidential. We share the following categories of information with third party service providers depending on the specific services provided:

  * Personal information (name, address, account number, SSN, etc.)
  * Account information (type of accounts, account balances, transaction history, etc.)
  * Transaction information (dates, amounts, locations, type of transactions, etc.)

We do not sell member information nor share your account numbers with independent third party marketers offering their products and services. We do not disclose or share information regarding our members or other consumers in ways that give rise to 'opt-out' or 'opt-in' election rights that you may have heard about. If we change this disclosure so that you would have such rights, we will notify you in advance.

_Sharing Information as Legally Required or Permitted_. We may share any member information of yours in response to a lawful request issued by a court, government agency, or regulatory authority or as permitted by law in order to administer or enforce your account. We may also share our experience information about you with credit bureaus. Our reporting to credit bureaus is governed by the Fair Credit Reporting Act, which affords you the right to make sure that your credit bureau reports are accurate.

**Our Confidentiality and Security Safeguards.** We maintain strict policies and security controls to assure that member information in our computer systems and files is protected. Our employees and agents are permitted access to member information that they may need to perform their jobs and to provide service to you. Our employees and agents have access to such member information as necessary to conduct a transaction or respond to your inquiries. All employees and agents are trained to respect member privacy. No one except our employees and agents has regular access to the Credit Union computer system and records storage. The Credit Union has established internal security controls, including physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to protect the information you provide us and the information we collect about you. We will continue to review our internal security controls to safeguard your member information as we employ new technology in the future.

#### Online Privacy Protections

On our web site, https://www.starone.org, you may apply for accounts and services and you may communicate with us via e-mail. To protect the information you provide us online, we use multiple levels of security. Our online applications and forms and our Online Banking service relies on industry standard "Secure Sockets Layer" (SSL) encryption to secure your transaction information and communication. However, if you send e-mail to service@starone.org it will not be secure. When you visit our web site, you can access information, without revealing your personal identity. If you input your member number and password to enter Online Banking, we will use "cookies" to authenticate you and track your visit for Online Banking sessions. These "cookies" will be used to help us identify you for future Online Banking sessions. A "cookie" is a piece of information that our web server stores on your computer hard drive and retrieves later. The "cookie" will not request, require or collect personal identity information other than the information used to authenticate you for Online Banking access.

#### Protecting Children's Information Privacy.

Our online financial services are not directed toward or designed for use by children. We do not knowingly solicit or collect data from children and we do not knowingly market to children online. We recognize that protecting children's identities and online privacy is important and that responsibility rests with us and with parents.

#### Privacy Policy Inquiries.

We reserve the right to amend this Policy in the future. If you have any questions about our privacy practices, contact us by calling (866) 543-5202 or (408) 543-5202, sending us an e-mail at [service@starone.org](mailto:service@starone.org), or writing to us at Star One Credit Union, P.O. Box 3643, Sunnyvale, CA 94088-3643.
